# **Dana Nobile**

# **Marketing Professional**

DanaGNobile@Gmail.com | (631) 672-7576 | Tampa, FL | https://dananobile.github.io/Portfolio/

## **Professional Summary:**

Marketing professional carrying over ten years' experience with a specialty in portfolio growth.

Campaign strategy efforts yield an average of 50% increase in social media engagement, 30% increase in website traffic, and 20% increase in new lead generation.

#### Skills:

<ul> <li>Campaign Strategy</li> </ul>	trategv
---------------------------------------	---------

- Content Marketing
- Inbound Marketing
- Email Automation
- Lead Generation
- SEO

- Hubspot
- Moz/ SEM Rush
- MailChimp
- HTML/CSS
- JavaScript/JQuery
- Facebook Bus. Mngr.
- WordPress
- Canva
- Jira | Asana | Wrike
- Google Search Console
- Google Analytics

#### **Certifications:**

- Hubspot, Growth Driven Design
- HubSpot, Inbound Marketing
- HubSpot, Contextual Marketing
- HubSpot, Marketing Software

- HubSpot, Email Marketing
- Google, Advanced Google Analytics
- SEM Rush, SEO Fundamentals
- SEMRush, Keyword Research

### **Professional Experience:**

SmartBug Media | HubSpot Elite Partner Marketing Agency

2021- Current

## **Inbound Marketing Manager**

- Develop strategy and identify KPIs to a diverse portfolio of of client- specializing in SaaS B2B marketing
- Identify and strategize optimal content opportunities based on competitive gap analysis and persona needs
- Partner with sales team in developing contract proposals to prospect clients
- Work in a variety of platforms to optimize website CRO- ie HubSpot, WordPress & Marketo
- Manage team members across departments on projects from start to finish- including website redesigns
- Develop and present custom, in-depth reporting on marketing ROI, including website performance, conversion rates, email campaigns and SEO positioning- coupled with suggestions to improve lacking areas

BluLeadz | HubSpot Diamond Partner Marketing Agency

2019-2021

### **Marketing Strategist**

- Develop strategies and identify KPIs to deliver a positive return on investment for clients
- Collaborate with my team of marketing consultants, designers, developers, copywriters, and video/paid specialists to meet client goals and optimally execute strategy
- Identify client challenges and offer solutions
- Communicate strategy plans and provide the "why" behind it
- Track, analyze and interpret campaign behavior
- Regularly perform portal audits to identify areas of opportunity
- Develop inbound performance reports to analyze and monitor inbound strategy effectiveness

#### **Senior Marketing Manager**

- Increased social media engagement by over 50%, and website traffic by 40% via lead generation
- tactics, landing pages, paid ads and email automation
- Responsible for directing corporate marketing department of Dental Service Organization
- servicing 60+ practices across the US, in 9 states with annual marketing budget of 2.8 million
- Counseled CEO on all marketing initiatives and responsible for driving marketing strategy
- Manage, craft and deliver all internal and external corporate communications
- Share internal company updates with regional directors and manager via mass communications
- Coordinated, planned and executed internal company trainings alongside HR
- Recruited and managed relationships with outside agencies, freelancers and consultants
- Created and implemented annual marketing strategy to grow revenue via website management,
- email campaigns, social media, direct mail, local advertising, reputation management, Google Listings, Google Ad Words, PPC, SEO, SEM
- Lead website production projects from inception to launch by partnering with content creation, design, development, SEO and video production teams

### Marketing 2 Go | Marketing Agency

2013 - 2016

### **Marketing Account Manager**

- Average increase of 30% in lead generation for each account
- Developed and executed marketing plans, content calendars and branding strategies for both
- B2B and B2C industries across multiple outlets including social networks, email campaigns,
- blogs and landing pages
- Focus areas of accounts: Real estate, property management and legal
- Developed, implemented Facebook and Instagram ads via Ads Manager
- Responsible for negotiating contracts and creating media packages within client's budget
- Strong ability to multitask and manage multiple brands, while developing deep understanding
- of a variety of business structures

Home & Self Defense Specialists | Palm Coast, FL

2010 - 2013

## **Co-Owner and Marketing Manager**

- Average annual sales increase 20% YoY via marketing efforts, and increased social media
- engagement by 80% overall. Promoted CWP classes via social media and print ads-increased
- average class average from 5 to 25 students, netting increase of over 2K per class
- Launched opening of a new retail and eCommerce store, including negotiating vendor
- contracts, buying inventory, competitive analysis, store layout/design, conceptualizing website
- Developed and led the execution of marketing and eCommerce plan among various customer
- segments and channels
- Managed all social media channels, maintained and managed company website, and designed
- and implemented email marketing campaigns
- Sought, established and managed vendor relations with wholesalers and outside agencies
- Prepared collateral and strategy for trade shows to capture new leads
- Managed P&L statement and budget for entire company

Marriott Properties | Long Island, NY

June 2006 – December 2010

#### Marketing Manager (December 2008-December 2010)

- Developed, planned, and executed programs as necessary to achieve revenue goals
- Crafted messages/materials for strategy and stayed within budget
- Liaise with key operators of each department to determine goals and marketing needs
- Liaises with hotel Director of Public Relations to provide communications tools as needed

## Marketing Coordinator (July 2006-December 2008)

- Responsible for assisting Director of Sales & Marketing in advertising initiatives
- Managed the property's website
- Assisted in choosing ideal advertising platforms and drafted necessary items for each, including
- radio ad scripts, print design and digital marketing materials
- Represented brand and created print brochures and collateral for bridal expos as well as coordinated and manage on-site trade shows; and assisted with marketing content calendar

# **Pre-Professional Experience:**

Hearst Publications | New York, NY Jan. 2006 - June 2006 | Editorial Intern Tallahassee Bride Magazine | Tallahassee, FL Dec. 2003 – May 2004 | Editorial Intern FSView FSU College Newspaper | Tallahassee, FL Jan. 2004 – May 2006 | Staff Writer

#### **Education:**

University of Central Florida | Certification | Web Development & Coding Certification | 2020 Florida State University | Bachelor of Science Degree | Marketing | 2006